I had been working with steve jobs at
Atari he was a consulting engineer for
Atari I was the chief draftsman product
development engineer so naturally I was
involved with all the engineers and the
jobs and I got pretty chummy over a span
of a couple of years and he in turn then
later on introduced me to Steve Wozniak
and he introduced me to Osmond act only
because they were having a minor dispute
over business matters they were thinking
about forming a company but there was a
dispute as to proprietorship of the
circuits that was had developed because
was with the genius and he but
everything he did he did for the fun of
it and he wanted to retain a
proprietorship of the circuitry so that
he could use it in other applications
and Jobs was trying to tell me couldn't
do that this would be the core of the
company and he was having a health front
I'm trying to get him to understand this
so we'll find bring him over to the
house we'll sit down we'll chat about it
what was a reasonable fellow and all I
had to do is lay it out for me finally
came around and in matter of fact in
less than an hour we were chatting and
he understood finally okay well Jobs was
so impressed with my ability as a
diplomat you know what a diplomat is as
a fellow who can tell you to go to hell
in a way that makes you look forward to
the trip okay anyway he said well we're
going to found the Apple computer
company that's it and he and Wozniak
would get forty five percent and i would
get ten percent as the tiebreaker
because jobs felt it in the event of any
further disputes that i would come down
on the side of reason and everything
went together i sat down immediately and
typed up the contract three contracts in
fact which we signed and set up registry
at the registrar's office in Santa Clara
California and the company Apple
computer company was founded and then 12
days later I went down to santa clara
county registrar's office and took my
name off the contract